{"Answer": "Global Sodium Consumption and Death from Cardiovascular Causes\n\nHigh sodium intake increases blood pressure , a risk factor for cardiovascular disease , but the effects of sodium intake on global cardiovascular mortality are uncertain .\n\nWe collected data from surveys on sodium intake as determined by urinary excretion and diet in persons from 66 countries ( accounting for 74.1 % of adults throughout the world ) , and we used these data to quantify the global consumption of sodium according to age , sex , and country . The effects of sodium on blood pressure , according to age , race , and the presence or absence of hypertension , were calculated from data in a new meta-analysis of 107 randomized interventions , and the effects of blood pressure on cardiovascular mortality , according to age , were calculated from a meta-analysis of cohorts . Cause-specific mortality was derived from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010 . Using comparative risk assessment , we estimated the cardiovascular effects of current sodium intake , as compared with a reference intake of 2.0 g of sodium per day , according to age , sex , and country .\n\nIn 2010 , the estimated mean level of global sodium consumption was 3.95 g per day , and regional mean levels ranged from 2.18 to 5.51 g per day . Globally , 1.65 million annual deaths from cardiovascular causes ( 95 % uncertainty interval ( confidence interval ) , 1.10 million to 2.22 million ) were attributed to sodium intake above the reference level ; 61.9 % of these deaths occurred in men and 38.1 % occurred in women . These deaths accounted for nearly 1 of every 10 deaths from cardiovascular causes ( 9.5 % ) . Four of every 5 deaths ( 84.3 % ) occurred in low - and middle-income countries , and 2 of every 5 deaths ( 40.4 % ) were premature ( before 70 years of age ) . The rate of death from cardiovascular causes associated with sodium intake above the reference level was highest in the country of Georgia and lowest in Kenya .\n\nIn this modeling study , 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular causes that occurred in 2010 were attributed to sodium consumption above a reference level of 2.0 g per day . ( Funded by the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation . )\n\n", "Topic": "cardio", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "level": 0, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "74.1 %": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"], "1 of every 10": ["Outcomes"], "9.5 %": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "74.1 %": ["Sample-size"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"], "1 of every 10": ["Effect-strength"], "9.5 %": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "A"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Sex": [], "Age": [], "Condition": [], "Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["A"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Duration": [], "Intensity": [], "Control": [], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Adverse-effects": [], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}, "Count": 1}, "Doggos_text": {"Location": "Participants were from 66 different countries", "Sample-size": "The data used accounted for 74.1% of the adults throughout the world.", "Intervention-general": "The study assessed the impact of sodium consumption.", "Outcomes-general": "The study measured death from cardiovascular causes.", "Effect-strength": "Sodium consumption was associated with 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular disease, which represent 9.5% or 1 of every 10 deaths of cardiovascular causes", "Conclusion-general": "Sodium consumption above a reference level of 2.0g a day was associated with 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular diseases."}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127", "children": [{"Answer": "High blood pressure is caused by too high of sodium intake and it will increase your likelihood of developing cardiovascular disease. Most people throughout the world get about 3.95g of sodium in their diet each day. There were 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular disease in 2010. Research discovered that many of these deaths were in people who had a much greater intake of sodium than the 3.95 per day. Many of these deaths were in low and middle income countries and were premature - meaning the person died before they should have. The country that was the most affected by this was Georgia but Kenya was least affected. This is why researchers are now saying that we should do our best to keep our sodium intake to around 2g per day. Doing so is healthier for us and will help prevent us from suffering from a premature death. Research was conducted by organizations like the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation.", "AssignmentId": "3NJM2BJS4XRSB16G4WY9XRU27IMCPB", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A25AJ66CYVUTBR", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3NJM2BJS4XRSB16G4WY9XRU27IMCPB", "children": [{"Answer": "Studies have shown that taking more sodium than 3.95g per day increases risk of high blood pressure which will likely increase one's chance of getting cardiovascular disease.  Specifically there were 1.65 million deaths from the disease and research shows they were getting over the threshold of 3.95g.  More specifically those affected were from low and middle income countries.  Due to this data from such organizations as the Bill and Melinda Gates foundation, researchers suggest reducing sodium intake to 2g per day,", "AssignmentId": "3M0BCWMB8WHZL5BB2IG9E1WGJVABWM", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3NJM2BJS4XRSB16G4WY9XRU27IMCPB", "WorkerId": "AXY0D2AMLKE2A", "Qualification": 0.7692307692307693, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3NJM2BJS4XRSB16G4WY9XRU27IMCPB_3M0BCWMB8WHZL5BB2IG9E1WGJVABWM", "children": [{"Answer": "Study shows that taking more than 3.95g of sodium per day increases risk of high blood pressure which may increase one's chance of getting cardiovascular disease causing 1.65 million deaths according to research. Researchers suggest reducing sodium intake to 2g per day.", "AssignmentId": "3GFK2QRXXA2XWPU218PWBFWO9K95W6", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3NJM2BJS4XRSB16G4WY9XRU27IMCPB_3M0BCWMB8WHZL5BB2IG9E1WGJVABWM", "WorkerId": "A2VNK2H6USLQTK", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3NJM2BJS4XRSB16G4WY9XRU27IMCPB_3M0BCWMB8WHZL5BB2IG9E1WGJVABWM_3GFK2QRXXA2XWPU218PWBFWO9K95W6", "children": [{"Answer": "Sodium intake of more than 3.95g per day increases one's chance of cardiovascular disease and should be limited to 2g per day.", "AssignmentId": "3JC6VJ2SAC40PCRZ03T4TQZXHA8A5K", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3NJM2BJS4XRSB16G4WY9XRU27IMCPB_3M0BCWMB8WHZL5BB2IG9E1WGJVABWM_3GFK2QRXXA2XWPU218PWBFWO9K95W6", "WorkerId": "A3RH84U74MARF5", "Qualification": 0.6923076923076923, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "C"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["B"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3NJM2BJS4XRSB16G4WY9XRU27IMCPB_3M0BCWMB8WHZL5BB2IG9E1WGJVABWM_3GFK2QRXXA2XWPU218PWBFWO9K95W6_3JC6VJ2SAC40PCRZ03T4TQZXHA8A5K", "children": [{"Answer": "2g per day of sodium is better to decrease risk of cardiovascular disease.", "AssignmentId": "3HRMW88U17B2W6EN00DXLMY6UL00MR", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3NJM2BJS4XRSB16G4WY9XRU27IMCPB_3M0BCWMB8WHZL5BB2IG9E1WGJVABWM_3GFK2QRXXA2XWPU218PWBFWO9K95W6_3JC6VJ2SAC40PCRZ03T4TQZXHA8A5K", "WorkerId": "AXY0D2AMLKE2A", "Qualification": 0.7692307692307693, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["B"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3NJM2BJS4XRSB16G4WY9XRU27IMCPB_3M0BCWMB8WHZL5BB2IG9E1WGJVABWM_3GFK2QRXXA2XWPU218PWBFWO9K95W6_3JC6VJ2SAC40PCRZ03T4TQZXHA8A5K_3HRMW88U17B2W6EN00DXLMY6UL00MR"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "Data was collected from people in 66 countries to understand sodium levels in diets around the world, and how high sodium might contribute to cardiovascular disease and related deaths. \r\rHigh sodium intake is responsible increasing blood pressure, and increased blood pressure can cause death from cardiovascular causes. 1.65 million annual deaths occur from cardiovascular causes that are attributed to high sodium intake. Men are at especially high risk to develop cardiovascular disease from high sodium intake, with 61.9% of the deaths that were studied occurring in men, and 38.1 deaths occurring in women. These deaths that were attributed to high sodium made up 9.5% of all deaths from cardiovascular causes. Deaths associated with high sodium intake occurred most often in the country of Georgia, and least in the country of Kenya. High sodium is considered to be intakes above the reference level of 2.0 g per day.", "AssignmentId": "3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDEQ4KXK", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A83OOIGU4606R", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"], "9.5 %": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"], "9.5 %": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDEQ4KXK", "children": [{"Answer": "Information was gathered from people residing in 66 countries. It was about sodium levels and their effect on diseases of the heart and related death. People who have a diet high in sodium are at risk of heart disease and high blood pressure. Men are more subsebtable to the effects with 61.9% of death compared to 38.1% with women dying from cardiovascular diseases. Only 9.5% of the deaths were connected to a high sodium diet. The country Georgia had the most deaths compared to Kenya. 2000 mg per day Is considered high sodium.", "AssignmentId": "37UEWGM5HUTT0BCX1RDELQBQ55V1RJ", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDEQ4KXK", "WorkerId": "A39GH5GG2B7KA1", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"66 country": ["Participants"], "9.5 %": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"66 country": ["Location"], "9.5 %": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDEQ4KXK_37UEWGM5HUTT0BCX1RDELQBQ55V1RJ", "children": [{"Answer": "A study was conducted on people who resided in 66 countries on the on how much sodium levels influenced cardiac disease.  61.9% of men and 38.1% of women die from cardiovascular disease.  9.5% of those deaths had high (2,000 mg) sodium diets.", "AssignmentId": "3MB8LZR5BGEK3E364HM04TYQ84NKL2", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDEQ4KXK_37UEWGM5HUTT0BCX1RDELQBQ55V1RJ", "WorkerId": "A1E66M679AFI3S", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"66 country": ["Participants"], "9.5 %": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"66 country": ["Location"], "9.5 %": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDEQ4KXK_37UEWGM5HUTT0BCX1RDELQBQ55V1RJ_3MB8LZR5BGEK3E364HM04TYQ84NKL2", "children": [{"Answer": "High (2,000 mg) sodium diets cause 9.5% of cardiac/cardiovascular disease deaths out of 100 men and women from 66 countries. ", "AssignmentId": "3X4JMASXCNU6DFAQ9BNO76NCIJ20B2", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDEQ4KXK_37UEWGM5HUTT0BCX1RDELQBQ55V1RJ_3MB8LZR5BGEK3E364HM04TYQ84NKL2", "WorkerId": "AW1SWNQFPIUKF", "Qualification": 0.7692307692307693, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"66 country": ["Participants"], "9.5 %": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"66 country": ["Location"], "9.5 %": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDEQ4KXK_37UEWGM5HUTT0BCX1RDELQBQ55V1RJ_3MB8LZR5BGEK3E364HM04TYQ84NKL2_3X4JMASXCNU6DFAQ9BNO76NCIJ20B2", "children": [{"Answer": "Diets high in salt cause 9.5% of cardiovascular disease deaths.", "AssignmentId": "35L9RVQFCP3WKEPS7AB4IOEHTRWHUZ", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDEQ4KXK_37UEWGM5HUTT0BCX1RDELQBQ55V1RJ_3MB8LZR5BGEK3E364HM04TYQ84NKL2_3X4JMASXCNU6DFAQ9BNO76NCIJ20B2", "WorkerId": "AVBRJBJONL47I", "Qualification": 1.0, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"9.5 %": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"9.5 %": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDEQ4KXK_37UEWGM5HUTT0BCX1RDELQBQ55V1RJ_3MB8LZR5BGEK3E364HM04TYQ84NKL2_3X4JMASXCNU6DFAQ9BNO76NCIJ20B2_35L9RVQFCP3WKEPS7AB4IOEHTRWHUZ"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "Data was collected from surveys on sodium intake as determined by urinary excretion and diet in people from 66 countries and was used to quantify the global consumption of sodium according to age, sex and country. The effects of sodium on blood pressure, according to age, race and the presence or absence of hypertension were calculated in a new meta-analysis of 107 random interventions. Cause specific mortality was derived from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010. The estimated mean level of global sodium consumption was 3.95g/day and regional mean levels ranged from 2.18 to 5.51g/day. Globally 1.65 million annual deaths from cardiovascular causes were attributed to sodium intake above the 2.0 g/day reference level; 61.9% were men and 38.1 were women. These deaths accounted for 1 of every 10 deaths from cardiovascular causes. 4 of every 5 deaths occurred in low and middle income countries and 2 out of 5 were premature before age 70. The highest death rates from cardiovascular causes associated with high sodium intake was in the country of Georgia and lowest in Kenya.", "AssignmentId": "3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA82LW4Q", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A98E8M4QLI9RS", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"], "1 of every 10": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"], "1 of every 10": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA82LW4Q", "children": [{"Answer": "In a study of sodium intake and its impact on cause specific mortality related to cardiovascular causes, results showed that globally, 1.65 million (or one out of 10) annual deaths from cardiovascular causes were attributable to sodium intake above 2.0 g/day reference level. Also considered in the study were aspects such as age, country, blood pressure, race and absence or presence of hypertension. The highest cardiovascular caused death counts related to high sodium consumption were in the country of Georgia and the lowest were in Kenya.", "AssignmentId": "3R0T90IZ1TXMYODH1D8M3IGA7W2CGL", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA82LW4Q", "WorkerId": "A37CE37LHUN8M6", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "60+", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA82LW4Q_3R0T90IZ1TXMYODH1D8M3IGA7W2CGL", "children": [{"Answer": "In a recent study or sodium intake as it relates to cardiac issues results showed that 1 out of 10 deaths from cardiovascular causes were related to high sodium intake. This study took into account age, country and blood pressure.", "AssignmentId": "358UUM7WR0O7BXRZQ7UNM0238GA7RF", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA82LW4Q_3R0T90IZ1TXMYODH1D8M3IGA7W2CGL", "WorkerId": "AD70PPBAJSCPV", "Qualification": 0.6153846153846154, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA82LW4Q_3R0T90IZ1TXMYODH1D8M3IGA7W2CGL_358UUM7WR0O7BXRZQ7UNM0238GA7RF", "children": [{"Answer": "A recent study noted that high sodium intake contributed to 10% of deaths from all cardiovascular-related causes.", "AssignmentId": "3R9WASFE201TSHSWI7MCWVHJFPGZFG", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA82LW4Q_3R0T90IZ1TXMYODH1D8M3IGA7W2CGL_358UUM7WR0O7BXRZQ7UNM0238GA7RF", "WorkerId": "A1SNL49AU2I5BV", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "40-60", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA82LW4Q_3R0T90IZ1TXMYODH1D8M3IGA7W2CGL_358UUM7WR0O7BXRZQ7UNM0238GA7RF_3R9WASFE201TSHSWI7MCWVHJFPGZFG", "children": [{"Answer": "In a study, high salt intake is linked to 10% of all cardiovascular deaths.", "AssignmentId": "3A7Y0R2P2P9KSOED0FPCE8T012YJXI", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA82LW4Q_3R0T90IZ1TXMYODH1D8M3IGA7W2CGL_358UUM7WR0O7BXRZQ7UNM0238GA7RF_3R9WASFE201TSHSWI7MCWVHJFPGZFG", "WorkerId": "A1WNHGZ8S46T3C", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "40-60", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA82LW4Q_3R0T90IZ1TXMYODH1D8M3IGA7W2CGL_358UUM7WR0O7BXRZQ7UNM0238GA7RF_3R9WASFE201TSHSWI7MCWVHJFPGZFG_3A7Y0R2P2P9KSOED0FPCE8T012YJXI"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "The risk of death from high sodium consumption is higher in low and middle-income countries such as Georgia and Kenya. The cardiovascular effects from the high sodium consumption are an increase in blood pressure which also is a risk factor for cardiovascular disease. The global study that was done in 2010 proved that the people who lived in \"poor\" countries and \"undereducated\" countries were at a higher risk for death from cardiovascular causes because they had a higher sodium intake. If these people had access to education about the consumption of foods and drinks high in sodium their total risk of death from cardiovascular causes would decrease. If they lower their sodium intake to even the reference intake of 2.0 g per day then their risk would decrease. In 2010 the mean level of global sodium consumption was 3.95 g per day. That is 1.95 g over the reference intake and greatly increases a persons risk of cardiovascular disease.", "AssignmentId": "3WETL7AQWUT05RSEROEU6ILRA5O530", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A329WHNJKAKTW7", "Qualification": 0.7692307692307693, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "C"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3WETL7AQWUT05RSEROEU6ILRA5O530", "children": [{"Answer": "In 2010 a global study showed that the average sodium consumption for a person worldwide was almost twice the recommended limit of 2.0g/day. Increased sodium intake increases the risk of cardiovascular disease. This risk is evidenced most in low/middle income countries where people are not as educated about the connection between elevated high blood pressure and the  increased cardiovascular risk associated with a high sodium intake. Education on limiting intake of high sodium food and drink would decrease deaths from cardiovascular disease.", "AssignmentId": "3GD6L00D3TI23VZ5WJHXZRHGZITM1D", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3WETL7AQWUT05RSEROEU6ILRA5O530", "WorkerId": "A8QOTDLW0QMPH", "Qualification": 0.6923076923076923, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "C"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3WETL7AQWUT05RSEROEU6ILRA5O530_3GD6L00D3TI23VZ5WJHXZRHGZITM1D", "children": [{"Answer": "Worldwide, the average sodium intake is almost twice the recommended limit, which is shown to increase the risk of cardiovascular disease. This is most evident in low/middle income countries where there is less health education. More education would reduce these deaths.", "AssignmentId": "3LEIZ60CDKKKR71JFLMKMZV8CJQZ9D", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3WETL7AQWUT05RSEROEU6ILRA5O530_3GD6L00D3TI23VZ5WJHXZRHGZITM1D", "WorkerId": "A1S6MEOVLLSVX2", "Qualification": 1.0, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "C"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["B"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3WETL7AQWUT05RSEROEU6ILRA5O530_3GD6L00D3TI23VZ5WJHXZRHGZITM1D_3LEIZ60CDKKKR71JFLMKMZV8CJQZ9D", "children": [{"Answer": "Sodium intake is roughly two times what is recommended. More education on sodium's effects would reduce deaths from cardiovascular issues.", "AssignmentId": "3HHRAGRYX9Q8S3NCDCB361O4SN3O9W", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3WETL7AQWUT05RSEROEU6ILRA5O530_3GD6L00D3TI23VZ5WJHXZRHGZITM1D_3LEIZ60CDKKKR71JFLMKMZV8CJQZ9D", "WorkerId": "A2Y9ZNZ0F24GHB", "Qualification": 1.0, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["B"], "Outcomes": ["A", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["B"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3WETL7AQWUT05RSEROEU6ILRA5O530_3GD6L00D3TI23VZ5WJHXZRHGZITM1D_3LEIZ60CDKKKR71JFLMKMZV8CJQZ9D_3HHRAGRYX9Q8S3NCDCB361O4SN3O9W", "children": [{"Answer": "People consume too much sodium and we need more education on the dangers. ", "AssignmentId": "3YJ6NA41JC1FJFCMEOFVKV7XYZ9JP5", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3WETL7AQWUT05RSEROEU6ILRA5O530_3GD6L00D3TI23VZ5WJHXZRHGZITM1D_3LEIZ60CDKKKR71JFLMKMZV8CJQZ9D_3HHRAGRYX9Q8S3NCDCB361O4SN3O9W", "WorkerId": "A1BDJJ3Z71CDKL", "Qualification": 0.6923076923076923, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["C", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["C"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3WETL7AQWUT05RSEROEU6ILRA5O530_3GD6L00D3TI23VZ5WJHXZRHGZITM1D_3LEIZ60CDKKKR71JFLMKMZV8CJQZ9D_3HHRAGRYX9Q8S3NCDCB361O4SN3O9W_3YJ6NA41JC1FJFCMEOFVKV7XYZ9JP5"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "While high sodium increases blood pressure and is a risk factor for cardiovascular disease the effects on sodium intake on global cardiovascular mortality are unknown. Data was collected from urine and diet from people in 66 countries which accounts for 74.1% of adults throughout the world. The effects of sodium on blood pressure according to age, race and presence of hypertension were calculated from data in a new meta analysis of 107 randomized interventions and the effects of blood pressure on cardiovascular mortality according to age were calculated from a meta-analysis of cohorts. Using comparative risk assessment, the cardiovascular effects of current sodium intake were calculated compared with a reference intake of 2.0 g of sodium per day according to age, sex and country. In 2010 the estimated mean level of global sodium consumption was 3.95 g a day. Globally, 1.65 million deaths were attributed to high sodium intake. 61.9% of these deaths occurred in men and 38.1% in women. 2 out of ever 5 deaths were before the age of 70. \r", "AssignmentId": "39LNWE0K4VHWG90CDSTPI0FWS4IIUZ", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A2YUCJ28XANFOX", "Qualification": 0.7692307692307693, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "High School", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "74.1 %": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "74.1 %": ["Sample-size"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "A"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["A"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_39LNWE0K4VHWG90CDSTPI0FWS4IIUZ", "children": [{"Answer": "From a large and diverse enough sample size to account for 74.1% of humans, researchers collected data to compare race, age, and the presence of hypertension to the level of sodium intake and its effect on blood pressure and cardiovascular mortality.  The metrics of sodium were defined by a comparison to the global average intake to postulate a connection between demographic and the 1.65 million deaths related to sodium intake.  61.9% of these deaths are men and 40% of these deaths occurred before the individual was 70 years old.", "AssignmentId": "333U7HK6IA06UI9W9FO0K1Q8KNJDJC", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_39LNWE0K4VHWG90CDSTPI0FWS4IIUZ", "WorkerId": "AY4QOQCWAJ0RN", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"74.1 %": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"74.1 %": ["Sample-size"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "A"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["A"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_39LNWE0K4VHWG90CDSTPI0FWS4IIUZ_333U7HK6IA06UI9W9FO0K1Q8KNJDJC", "children": [{"Answer": "Researchers studied the effect of sodium intake on blood pressure and cardiovascular deaths across race, age, and hypertension status. They found that, out of related 1.65 millions deaths, men accounted for 61.9% with 40% of the deaths occurring before the age of 70. ", "AssignmentId": "3YT88D1N09J3NADHYBI087498IL3KW", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_39LNWE0K4VHWG90CDSTPI0FWS4IIUZ_333U7HK6IA06UI9W9FO0K1Q8KNJDJC", "WorkerId": "AO33H4GL9KZX9", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "40-60", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_39LNWE0K4VHWG90CDSTPI0FWS4IIUZ_333U7HK6IA06UI9W9FO0K1Q8KNJDJC_3YT88D1N09J3NADHYBI087498IL3KW", "children": [{"Answer": "In this research states sodium intake on blood pressure and cardiovascular deaths across race, age and hypertension status.  ", "AssignmentId": "3STRJBFXOXC8MRBBDQORQK872PQTKB", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_39LNWE0K4VHWG90CDSTPI0FWS4IIUZ_333U7HK6IA06UI9W9FO0K1Q8KNJDJC_3YT88D1N09J3NADHYBI087498IL3KW", "WorkerId": "A1DOY340I9VN92", "Qualification": 0.38461538461538464, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_39LNWE0K4VHWG90CDSTPI0FWS4IIUZ_333U7HK6IA06UI9W9FO0K1Q8KNJDJC_3YT88D1N09J3NADHYBI087498IL3KW_3STRJBFXOXC8MRBBDQORQK872PQTKB", "children": [{"Answer": "Research shows the effect of sodium intake on heart health.", "AssignmentId": "3GS6S824SRI1ME0858LI5WWA1K0WN9", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_39LNWE0K4VHWG90CDSTPI0FWS4IIUZ_333U7HK6IA06UI9W9FO0K1Q8KNJDJC_3YT88D1N09J3NADHYBI087498IL3KW_3STRJBFXOXC8MRBBDQORQK872PQTKB", "WorkerId": "A1RH1NL51JR9TA", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["C", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["C"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_39LNWE0K4VHWG90CDSTPI0FWS4IIUZ_333U7HK6IA06UI9W9FO0K1Q8KNJDJC_3YT88D1N09J3NADHYBI087498IL3KW_3STRJBFXOXC8MRBBDQORQK872PQTKB_3GS6S824SRI1ME0858LI5WWA1K0WN9"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "High blood pressure is a risk factor for cardiovascular diseases and eating high sodium foods increases blood pressure, but its effect on global cardiovascular mortality is uncertain.\rA data collected from 66 countries on sodium intake was used to quantify global consumption of sodium by age, sex and country. \rGlobally 1.65 million annual deaths from cardiovascular causes were attributed to high sodium intake. The gender difference was 61.9% men and 38.1% women and they were 9.5% of deaths from cardiovascular diseases. 4 of every 5 deaths occurred in low and middle income countries, and 2 of every 5 deaths were premature (before the age 70). The rate of death caused by cardiovascular causes resulted from high sodium intake was highest in country of Georgia and lowest in Kenya.\rAccording to this modeling study, in 2010, a total of 1.65 million deaths were attributed to high sodium consumption (above reference level 2.0g per day).", "AssignmentId": "3F0BG9B9MQ8G8Y3L42MHUWV0ACOY7O", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AISNLDPD2DFEG", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"], "9.5 %": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"], "9.5 %": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3F0BG9B9MQ8G8Y3L42MHUWV0ACOY7O", "children": [{"Answer": "Data collection from 66 countries on sodium intake was taken. Globally 1.65 million deaths occur each year due to cardiovascular causes attributed to high sodium intake. 61.9% of men and 38.1% of women is the gender difference and account for 9.5% of deaths from cardiovascular disease. 4 out of 5 deaths happened in low to middle income countries. 2 out of 5 deaths were premature (before the age of 70). The highest rate of death was in the country Georgia and lowest in Kenya.", "AssignmentId": "3QRYMNZ7FZ29UXWEA3G7ICPBWQ7NTY", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3F0BG9B9MQ8G8Y3L42MHUWV0ACOY7O", "WorkerId": "A2ELH7YDLFNJUZ", "Qualification": 1.0, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"66 country": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"], "9.5 %": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"66 country": ["Location"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"], "9.5 %": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3F0BG9B9MQ8G8Y3L42MHUWV0ACOY7O_3QRYMNZ7FZ29UXWEA3G7ICPBWQ7NTY", "children": [{"Answer": "Sodium information was taken from people globally. High sodium causes cardiovascular issues which lead to 1.65 million deaths globally, with the highest death rate in Georgia. Men were more affected than woman and 80 percent happened in lower and middle income areas. ", "AssignmentId": "3X66WABAJX3YLOHY8KXLAFCG10GG3G", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3F0BG9B9MQ8G8Y3L42MHUWV0ACOY7O_3QRYMNZ7FZ29UXWEA3G7ICPBWQ7NTY", "WorkerId": "A17MUXOICSH29I", "Qualification": 0.46153846153846156, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3F0BG9B9MQ8G8Y3L42MHUWV0ACOY7O_3QRYMNZ7FZ29UXWEA3G7ICPBWQ7NTY_3X66WABAJX3YLOHY8KXLAFCG10GG3G", "children": [{"Answer": "Georgia has the highest death rate related to sodium. Sodium related deaths are more prevalent in men and low and middle income areas. ", "AssignmentId": "3IO1LGZLKAIIPSYY8OJVP572NH968I", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3F0BG9B9MQ8G8Y3L42MHUWV0ACOY7O_3QRYMNZ7FZ29UXWEA3G7ICPBWQ7NTY_3X66WABAJX3YLOHY8KXLAFCG10GG3G", "WorkerId": "A2Q3FS9G8ITCN7", "Qualification": 0.7692307692307693, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["C", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["C"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3F0BG9B9MQ8G8Y3L42MHUWV0ACOY7O_3QRYMNZ7FZ29UXWEA3G7ICPBWQ7NTY_3X66WABAJX3YLOHY8KXLAFCG10GG3G_3IO1LGZLKAIIPSYY8OJVP572NH968I", "children": [{"Answer": "Sodium related deaths in Georgia are especially high middle income men.", "AssignmentId": "386PBUZZXGIPSUXOMWMO3EYDUVWLJA", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3F0BG9B9MQ8G8Y3L42MHUWV0ACOY7O_3QRYMNZ7FZ29UXWEA3G7ICPBWQ7NTY_3X66WABAJX3YLOHY8KXLAFCG10GG3G_3IO1LGZLKAIIPSYY8OJVP572NH968I", "WorkerId": "A3723CQM6I92CU", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "15-24", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["B"], "Outcomes": ["C", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["B"], "Outcomes-general": ["C"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3F0BG9B9MQ8G8Y3L42MHUWV0ACOY7O_3QRYMNZ7FZ29UXWEA3G7ICPBWQ7NTY_3X66WABAJX3YLOHY8KXLAFCG10GG3G_3IO1LGZLKAIIPSYY8OJVP572NH968I_386PBUZZXGIPSUXOMWMO3EYDUVWLJA"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "A global study was done on whether high sodium intake, which increases blood pressure is a risk factor for cardiovascular disease and deaths associated with that.  They collected data accounting for 74.1% of adults throughout the world.  They then randomly selected 107 people and then broke it down by age, sex and country.  The study indicated that average global consumption was 3.95 grams per day but these levels ranged from 2.18 to 5.51 per day, by various regions.  What the study found was that 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular causes that occurred in 2010 were attributed to sodium consumption was above the 2.0 grams per day.  This study was founded by the bill and Melinda Gates Foundation.  It was interesting to note that the highest levels of death from sodium intake was highest in the country of Georgia and lowest in Kenya.  So as you can see, sodium intake varied greatly by regions.  ", "AssignmentId": "3KV0LJBBH36QW0YMUDWC5IZT3FBRM0", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AAN06KVDS2XRY", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "60+", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "74.1 %": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "74.1 %": ["Sample-size"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "A"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["A"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3KV0LJBBH36QW0YMUDWC5IZT3FBRM0", "children": [{"Answer": "A study funded by the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation studied Sodium Chloride (salt) consumption in the world, accounting for 74.1% of adults, the lowest consumption being in the nation of Kenya and the highest in the nation of Georgia. One hundred and seven (107) people of differing age, gender, and nationality were randomly chosen to study the supposed risk of 1.65 million deaths per year from salt consumption above 2 grams per day. The global average was 3.95 grams of salt per day per person, but ranged from 2.18 to 5.51 grams.", "AssignmentId": "3G2UL9A02EZEPETFYJRPB5B7C4D67J", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3KV0LJBBH36QW0YMUDWC5IZT3FBRM0", "WorkerId": "A1WNHGZ8S46T3C", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "40-60", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"74.1 %": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"74.1 %": ["Sample-size"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "A"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["A"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3KV0LJBBH36QW0YMUDWC5IZT3FBRM0_3G2UL9A02EZEPETFYJRPB5B7C4D67J", "children": [{"Answer": "The highest consumption of salt in the world is the nation of Georgia, the lowest Kenya. A study with 107 randomly chosen people was taken to study a supposed risk of 1.65 millions in deaths per year from salt consumption above 2 grams per day. The global average is 3.95.", "AssignmentId": "37FMASSAYDCHKAR6D1CUDAN845RIB7", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3KV0LJBBH36QW0YMUDWC5IZT3FBRM0_3G2UL9A02EZEPETFYJRPB5B7C4D67J", "WorkerId": "A12I4JOVZ1HZW8", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["D", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["D"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3KV0LJBBH36QW0YMUDWC5IZT3FBRM0_3G2UL9A02EZEPETFYJRPB5B7C4D67J_37FMASSAYDCHKAR6D1CUDAN845RIB7", "children": [{"Answer": "a study was conducted on to assess salt consumption and the risk of death. 1.65 million deaths a year occur from high salt consumption. ", "AssignmentId": "3UJ1CZ6IZIA4P8DTH3FVEQT33GLS54", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3KV0LJBBH36QW0YMUDWC5IZT3FBRM0_3G2UL9A02EZEPETFYJRPB5B7C4D67J_37FMASSAYDCHKAR6D1CUDAN845RIB7", "WorkerId": "A2L53B1MI02U0W", "Qualification": 0.6923076923076923, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["B"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3KV0LJBBH36QW0YMUDWC5IZT3FBRM0_3G2UL9A02EZEPETFYJRPB5B7C4D67J_37FMASSAYDCHKAR6D1CUDAN845RIB7_3UJ1CZ6IZIA4P8DTH3FVEQT33GLS54", "children": [{"Answer": "A study found that 1.65 million people die from salt consumption each year", "AssignmentId": "3AMW0RGHOENB2537TM7ND2OE7MRPNY", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3KV0LJBBH36QW0YMUDWC5IZT3FBRM0_3G2UL9A02EZEPETFYJRPB5B7C4D67J_37FMASSAYDCHKAR6D1CUDAN845RIB7_3UJ1CZ6IZIA4P8DTH3FVEQT33GLS54", "WorkerId": "ACM87U430O96Z", "Qualification": 1.0, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["C", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["C"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3KV0LJBBH36QW0YMUDWC5IZT3FBRM0_3G2UL9A02EZEPETFYJRPB5B7C4D67J_37FMASSAYDCHKAR6D1CUDAN845RIB7_3UJ1CZ6IZIA4P8DTH3FVEQT33GLS54_3AMW0RGHOENB2537TM7ND2OE7MRPNY"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "High sodium intake increases blood pressure but the effects of sodium on cardiovascular mortality are uncertain. \r\rThe effects of sodium on blood pressure, according to demographics and the presence or absence of hypertension were calculated from a new meta-analysis and the effects of blood pressure on cardiovascular mortality were calculated. We estimated the cardiovascular effects of current sodium intake according to demographics. \r\rIn 2010, the mean level of global sodium consumption was 3.95 g per day and regional mean levels ranged from 2.18 to 5.51 g per day. Globally, 1.65 million annual deaths were attributed to high sodium intake; 61.9% of these deaths occurred in men and 38.1% in women. These deaths accounted for nearly 1 of 10 deaths from cardiovascular causes. 4 of 5 deaths occurred in low and middle-income countries, and 2 of 5 deaths were premature. The rate of death associated with sodium intake above the reference level was highest in Georgia and lowest in Kenya. \r\rIn this study, 1.65 million deaths from were attributed to sodium consumption above a reference level.", "AssignmentId": "3I7DHKZYGOLVL387BJFW7RAOEWE5FX", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A1CUPUT2GVV8CU", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "15-24", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3I7DHKZYGOLVL387BJFW7RAOEWE5FX", "children": [{"Answer": "According to demographics and calculated meta-analysis, having a high amount of sodium in the diet increases blood pressure. Studies have not yet shown the effects that sodium has on cardiovascular death, though. In 2010, it was shown that 1.65 million deaths were directly associated with high amounts of sodium consumption above the normal reference levels. This data also showed that the most deaths occurred in low and middle-income countries, with Georgia having the highest reference level and Kenya with the lowest.", "AssignmentId": "3CN4LGXD5Y9JPBL224OARKBQKBOY4X", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3I7DHKZYGOLVL387BJFW7RAOEWE5FX", "WorkerId": "A34RU3V8G203GN", "Qualification": 0.6153846153846154, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "15-24", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3I7DHKZYGOLVL387BJFW7RAOEWE5FX_3CN4LGXD5Y9JPBL224OARKBQKBOY4X", "children": [{"Answer": "Demographics and calculated meta-analysis, especially from low and middle-income countries like Georgia and Kenya show that a high sodium diet increases blood pressure. In 2010 1.65 millions deaths were directly associated with high sodium.", "AssignmentId": "3PXX5PX6LYJ2ES881DKHWCZPRXIBAS", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3I7DHKZYGOLVL387BJFW7RAOEWE5FX_3CN4LGXD5Y9JPBL224OARKBQKBOY4X", "WorkerId": "A9BVDYQU2VTIJ", "Qualification": 0.7692307692307693, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["B"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3I7DHKZYGOLVL387BJFW7RAOEWE5FX_3CN4LGXD5Y9JPBL224OARKBQKBOY4X_3PXX5PX6LYJ2ES881DKHWCZPRXIBAS", "children": [{"Answer": "Meta-analysis from low & middle-income counties (Georgia and Kenya) indicate that high-sodium intake increases blood pressure.", "AssignmentId": "3E1QT0TDFQUYICTZAPSKM8X7W808IA", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3I7DHKZYGOLVL387BJFW7RAOEWE5FX_3CN4LGXD5Y9JPBL224OARKBQKBOY4X_3PXX5PX6LYJ2ES881DKHWCZPRXIBAS", "WorkerId": "A2H1QUGX0SOUMH", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "60+", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["D", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["C", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["D"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["C"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3I7DHKZYGOLVL387BJFW7RAOEWE5FX_3CN4LGXD5Y9JPBL224OARKBQKBOY4X_3PXX5PX6LYJ2ES881DKHWCZPRXIBAS_3E1QT0TDFQUYICTZAPSKM8X7W808IA", "children": [{"Answer": "High sodium intake increase blood pressure according to meta-analysis.", "AssignmentId": "30IQTZXKALRDQIDRE7F6W3E41QL0XE", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127_3I7DHKZYGOLVL387BJFW7RAOEWE5FX_3CN4LGXD5Y9JPBL224OARKBQKBOY4X_3PXX5PX6LYJ2ES881DKHWCZPRXIBAS_3E1QT0TDFQUYICTZAPSKM8X7W808IA", "WorkerId": "APXMWCW8VUJZ8", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "40-60", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["C", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["C"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3I7DHKZYGOLVL387BJFW7RAOEWE5FX_3CN4LGXD5Y9JPBL224OARKBQKBOY4X_3PXX5PX6LYJ2ES881DKHWCZPRXIBAS_3E1QT0TDFQUYICTZAPSKM8X7W808IA_30IQTZXKALRDQIDRE7F6W3E41QL0XE"}]}]}]}]}]}